Ramakrishnan Sundara Raman

PhD Candidate, University of Michigan

☑ ramaks@umich.edu

• https://ramakrishnansr.com/

in ramakrishnansundararaman

Fifth-year PhD Candidate in Computer Science with expertise in Internet security, privacy and measurements. Published 9 conference papers (5 first author), 2 workshop papers (1 first author), 3 technical reports, and 2 posters. Recipient of an IRTF Applied Networking Research Prize (ANRP), a Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship, and an OTF Information Controls Fellowship. Experienced in developing large-scale networking and measurement tools that detect attacks on reachability of online services.

Education

 PhD Candidate, University of Michigan in Computer Science and Engineering CGPA: 3.95 out of 4

2018 – Present

Awards: IRTF ANRP, HotPETs Best Talk, Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship, OTF Information Controls Fellowship, North Campus Deans' MLK Spirit Award, CSE GSI Honorable Mention

Bachelor of Technology, Vellore Institute of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering
CGPA: 9.69 out of 10
2013 – 2017

Awards: 2nd rank out of 648 in CSE

Experience

Research Intern at Cloudflare Inc.
Developed network data analysis tools for detecting large-scale traffic tampering from an operator's point of view.

OTF Senior ICFP Fellow in Information Controls at The Citizen Lab November 2021 – July 2022
Researched novel measurement methods for locating and examining network censorship devices and studied their deployments in different countries.

O Graduate Student Instructor at *The University of Michigan* Led a graduate-level computer and network security class.

august 2020 – December 2020

Associate Consultant at Microsoft Global Delivery
Contributed to enterprise systems for business applications that can deliver value to large.

Research Intern at The University of Maryland
Built measurement and analysis tools to study last-mile residential Internet outages in areas affected by severe weather conditions.

Selected Publications (2 of 11)

Network Measurement Methods for Locating and Examining Censorship Devices

R. Sundara Raman*, M. Wang*, J.Dalek, J. Mayer, and R. Ensafi

ACM Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), December 2022

TRTF Applied Networking Research Prize

♦ https://ramakrishnansr.com/assets/censorship_devices.pdf

* Both authors contributed equally to this research

O Censored Planet: An Internet-wide, Longitudinal Censorship Observatory

R. Sundara Raman, P. Shenoy, K. Kohls, and R. Ensafi

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), November 2020

• https://ramakrishnansr.com/assets/censoredplanet.pdf

Activities

O PC Member at FOCI'21

Served as a technical program committee member for ACM SIGCOMM 2021 Workshop on Free and Open Communications on the Internet (FOCI 21).

Outreach Chair at CSEG
Arranged and managed outreach events that aimed at spreading knowledge about computer science in various schools, colleges and groups.